SURIM OH

soh31@ucsc.edu

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interests lie broadly in computer architecture and hardware-software interface. I have recently been working on the topic of fetch-directed instruction prefetching in modern processors to improve the CPU performance for datacenter workloads with large instruction footprints.

EDUCATION

University of California, Santa Cruz PhD Student in Computer Science and Engineering	Santa Cruz, CA, USA Sep 2020 - Present
\cdot Advisor: Professor Heiner Litz, Total GPA: $4.0/4.0$	
Seoul National University Master of Science in Computer Science and Engineering	Seoul, South Korea Feb 2015 - Feb 2017
· Advisor: Professor Bernhard Egger, Total GPA: 3.52/4.0	
\cdot Thesis: Hierarchical Manycore Resource Management Framework using	Control Processors [pdf]
Sogang University	Seoul, South Korea

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering Total GPA: 3.70/4.0 (95.8/100), Summa Cum Laude

· Exchange student at Northern Arizona University

AZ, USA, Spring 2014

Feb 2011 - Feb 2015

WORK EXPERIENCE

Meta	Sunnyvale, California, USA
ASIC Engineer Intern, Architecture	June 2024 - Sep 2024
Akeana	San Jose, California, USA
PhD Intern	June 2023 - Sep 2023
SAP Labs Korea	Seoul, South Korea
Developer	Jan 2018 - Sep 2020
Hyundai Motor Company R&D Division	Hwaseong, South Korea
Engineer	Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

SKILLS

C, C++, Python, Bash, Scarab simulator, Intel Perf, DynamoRIO, Verilog, Magic, OpenCL, Intel PCM, LLVM, HSIM-TQSIM (System C-based) manycore simulator

PUBLICATIONS

ISCA 2024: <u>Surim Oh</u>, Mingsheng Xu, Tanvir Ahmed Khan, Baris Kasikci, Heiner Litz. UDP: Utility-Driven Fetch Directed Instruction Prefetching. *In the 51th International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA)*, 2024

M.S. Thesis: <u>Surim Oh</u>. Hierarchical Manycore Resource Management Framework using Control Processors. Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea, February 2017. [pdf] [slides]

TPDS 2019: Younghyun Cho, <u>Surim Oh</u>, and Bernhard Egger. Performance Modeling of Parallel Loops on Multi-Socket Platforms using Queueing Systems. In *IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS)*, in press, available online, September 2019. [pdf]

MULTIPROG 2017: Younghyun Cho, <u>Surim Oh</u>, and Bernhard Egger. Cooperative Parallel Runtimes for Multicores. Presented at the 10th International Workshop on Programmability and Architectures for Heterogeneous Multicores, January 2017. [pdf]

CATC 2016: <u>Surim Oh</u>, Younghyun Cho, and Bernhard Egger. Efficient Resource Management for Many-cores with Centralized L2 Caches using Distributed Control Processors. *Presented at the 7th Compiler, Architectures and Tools Conference*, September 2016. [pdf] [slides]

PACT 2016: Younghyun Cho, <u>Surim Oh</u>, and Bernhard Egger. Online Scalability Characterization of Data-parallel Programs on Many Cores. In *Proceedings of the 25th International Conference on Parallel Architectures and Compilation Techniques (PACT)*, September 2016. [pdf]

JSSPP 2016: Younghyun Cho, <u>Surim Oh</u>, and Bernhard Egger. Adaptive Space-shared Scheduling for Shared-memory Parallel Programs. Presented at the 20th Workshop on Job Scheduling Strategies for Parallel Processing, May 2016. In Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNCS), Volume 10353, July 2016. [pdf]

PATENTS

US Patent 2018A: Bernhard Egger, <u>Surim Oh</u>, Younghyun Cho, Dong-hoon Yoo. Method of processing OpenCL Kernel and Computing Device Therefor. *US Patent 20180181443A1*, June 2018. Worldwide applications in KR, EP, CN, JP including US.

US Patent 2018B: Bernhard Egger, Younghyun Cho, <u>Surim Oh</u>. Dong-hoon Yoo. Computing devices and methods of allocating power to plurality of cores in each computing device. *US Patent* 20180246554A1, August 2018. Worldwide applications in KR, CN including US.

RESEARCH AND PROJECT EXPERIENCE

University of California, Santa Cruz *PhD Student*

Santa Cruz, CA, USA Sep 2020 - Present

- · Working on CPU frontend in modern processors.
 - Studied a state-of-the-art Fetch Directed instruction Prefetching (FDIP) on a microprocessor simulator, Scarab, and the performance impact of FDIP on frontend-bound applications with large instruction footprints.
 - Introduce Utility-Driven FDIP (UDP) by learning the performance impact of running-ahead distance of FDIP and the usefulness of instruction cache lines for optimal running-ahead distance and filtering mechanisms.

SAP Labs Korea

Developer

Seoul, South Korea Jan 2018 - Sep 2020

- · SAP HANA Database Management System
 - Table replication technology between HANA-to-otherDB or HANA-to-HANA for scaling out mixed OLTP/OLAP workloads in main-memory databases.
 - Contributed to design and implementation of table replication framework to generate and collect replication logs in transactional order with minimum source side cost.

 Design and implementation of log formats and protocols for querying the logs from any other database systems to be compatible with other general database systems.

Hyundai Motor Company R&D Division Engineer

Hwaseong, South Korea Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

- · Vehicle data monitoring system
 - Data monitoring framework to collect in-vehicle data from a great number of distributed ECUs and to save the data in a remote centralized server.
 - Contributed to design and development of the data collection framework that allows other research engineers to exploit specific data suitable for research in related fields.
 - Design and development of a merge tool for video data from testing cars to develop Advanced Driver Assistance Systems technology.

Computer System And Platform Laboratory, Seoul National University Seoul, South Korea Graduate Researcher

Feb 2015 - Feb 2017

- · Worked on resource management on manycore SoC architecture.
 - Developed manycore resource management techniques in consideration of runtime scheduling overhead and power consumption exploiting architecture support of tiny control processors. -CATC 2016, M.S. Thesis, US Patent 2018A, US Patent 2018B.
 - Distributed dynamic scheduling overheads through hierarchical core resource allocation for simultaneously running OpenCL applications.
 - Worked on implementation on top of a TQSIM-HSIM (Timed QEMU-based & SystemC-based) manycore simulator.
 - Collaborated with four other research groups from Seoul National University; architecture design, manycore simulator, programming model, and applications with 96-core Samsung research processor (research project with Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology).
 - Presented at HumanTech Paper Award organized by Samsung (not awarded).
- · Contributed to performance modeling on NUMA architectures.
 - An analytical performance model based on queueing theory to estimate the resource utilization on multiprocessor systems for parallel programs - PACT 2016, TPDS 2019.
 - Developed a tool for the performance model to query hardware performance counters related to the NUMA interconnection network in Intel/AMD systems.

AWARD

SnuMAP: 2nd prize in 10th Open Source Software World Challenge
SNU Manycore Profiler for Big-Data with SNU team

Seoul, South Korea

December 2016

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Computer Architecture (CSE120), UC Santa Cruz

Teaching Assistant

Computer Architecture, Seoul National University

Teaching Assistant

Fall 2023, Winter 2023, Fall 2021

Spring 2016, Fall 2015

Teaching Assistant

REFERENCES

Prof. Heiner Litz (University of California, Santa Cruz)

E-Mail: hlitz@ucsc.edu